第四季 第九集
S04E09: Bug
我自己来  我自己来
I got it, I got it.
天啊  玛丽你好烦
Jesus, You're like a bee at a damn picnic, Marie.
早啊
Morning
早啊  哥们儿
Hey buddy
准备好疯狂一下了吗
Get get you rocks on?
瞧  我就知道
See, I knew it.
矿物展其实是你们看脱衣舞的暗号吧
Mineral show just some sort of guy code for strip club.
你有单身的朋友想一起去吗
Hey, you get any singles?
别让他太疯了好吗
Don't let him get too crazy, ok?
他要是再买个大石头回来
Cram one more giant geode in here
我们就只能去睡车库了
we'll be sleeping in the garage.
-我自己能来  -好好
- I got it, I got it. - I'm sorry.
天啊
Christ.
真是人生中最漫长的一周
Longest week ever.
希望能得到点有用的东西
I just hope we get something good, you know?
帮我祈祷吧
Keep your fingers crossed.
放松点  哥们儿  又不是拍谍战电影
Relax, buddy. This ain't no spy movie.
倒比较像洛奇
It's more like Rocky, you know?
抓住坏人
Get the bad guy!
这是老虎的眼睛  这是战斗的快感*
It's the eye of the tiger, it's the thrill of the fight
一起反抗让他们生存*
Risin' up to keep 'em alive
你  你  你干嘛呢  干嘛回来
What-- What-- What are you doing, buddy?
准备走
Leaving.
不行  你得像上次一样
No, you got to go inside
进去买点东西  免得被人怀疑
and order something like last time to avoid suspicion.
再说了  我还想来杯香草奶昔呢
Besides, I want a vanilla shake.
一会从免下车窗口买
We'll use the drive-through.
好了  来看看我们查到些什么
All right, baby. Let's see what we got.
搞什么
What the hell?
瞧这些
Look at this. Bom, bom, bom, bom, bom.
工作  家  工作  家
That's work, that's home, that's work, that's home.
这家伙每天两点一线吗
What, this guy goes two places every day all week?
难以置信
It's unbelievable.
狗娘养的炸鸡店老板
Chicken-slinging son of a bitch.
汉克  有没有可能
Hank, is it possible that...
只是可能
maybe, just maybe...
他不是你要找的人
he's not your guy?
他这么清白反而可疑
Oh, a guy this clean's got to be dirty.
哥们儿  他在玩什么把戏
What's the play here, buddy?
怎么才能抓住这个人
How do I get this guy?
是啊
Yeah.
怎么办呢
How?
喂  你好
Yes, hi.
我住在多斯维尔 4900街区
I live on the 4900 block of Doswell Place,
我发现一个非常可疑的人
and I want to report a very suspicious man
正在监视我的邻居
who's lurking in my neighborhood.
他开一辆蓝色轿车
He's sitting in a blue sedan,
盯着一栋房子
and he-- he's been staring at a particular house
很长时间了
for a very long time.
谢谢  非常感谢
Thank you. Thank you so much.
可以的话真是太感谢了
If you would, I would appreciate it.
好了
All right.
准备开工吧
So I guess we better get started.
我已经做完了
I already did.
是吗
Yeah?
能给我一只吗
You got one of those for me?
什么
One of those what?
香烟
Cigarette.
那东西还在  好么
It's still in there, all right?
我还没找到下手的机会
I didn't get a chance yet.
给我就是了
Just give me one.
你最近在干嘛
So what have you been up to?
什么
What?
就是每天怎么过的啊
You know, just a day in the life.
你工作完之后都干嘛
What do you do after work?
回家  看电视
Go home, watch TV.
看什么
What do you watch?
不知道  随便看
I don't know. Stuff.
比如呢
Like what?
比如
Like, uh...
冰路前行
Ice Road Truckers.
讲什么的
What happens on that one?
讲在冰上开车的人们
Guys drive on ice.
我会做的
I am going to do it.
得吸气才行
You got to inhale, by the way.
你到底怎么了  癌症得的还不够吗
What the hell, man, don't you have enough cancer already?
我说了我要做
Look, I said...I'd do it.
就一定会做的
I'll do it.
好吧  有什么关系
Yeah, well, what does it matter?
反正我们都是要死的人了
We're both dead men anyway.
现在不方便说话吗
Am I, uh, catching you at a bad time?
方便  我有时间
No, I have a few minutes.
我们儿子说
So Mr. I'm Almost 16 So Leave Me Alone
不想大肆庆祝他的生日
doesn't want a big thing for his birthday.
只想和朋友一起过
He just wants to hang out with his friends,
我觉得无所谓  你呢
which is fine by me. You?
我也觉得无所谓
Fine by me.
好吧  所以我就想
Okay. So I figured, uh,
就办个不起眼的家庭聚会  不搞正式的派对
low-key family dinner, no official party,
我们要咬紧牙关
and we bite the bullet and...
给他买辆车
buy him a car--
我想  最好是二手车
Uh, used, I was thinking, would be best.
但是车龄不能超过五年
But no more than five years old.
带安全气囊  质量合格等等
Air bags, safety rated, all that.
你对买什么样的车有想法吗
Do you, um, have any thoughts on what kind,
还是我就直接去...
or should I just go ahead and--
行啊  你就直接去吧
Yeah. No, you just go ahead.
好吧
Okay.
听着  还有一件事
Listen. On another subject,
我得告诉你
I just wanted to tell you that
洗车店生意很好
business is good.
非常好
Really good.
好到了我觉得  你或许...
So good that I'm thinking maybe...
或许你不必再打那一份工了
you don't even need to work your second job.
你开始盈利了?
You're turning a profit?
快了
We're coming close.
再给我们一两个月
Give us another month or two,
我们就能盈利了
and, uh, yeah, we'll be there.
说了这么多
All of this to say
或许你该考虑金盆洗手了
maybe you could start thinking about an exit strategy.
我正在努力
I'm working on it.
那好
Ok.
喂
Hello.
嗨  伙计  吵醒你了吗
Hey, buddy. Wake you?
没有  汉克  我起来了
No, Hank, I'm up.
那就好  干什么呢
Oh, good. Uh, what you doing?
我在...
I'm, uh...
听着  我不废话了
Hey, listen, I-I'll cut to it.
我得再请你帮个忙
I got another favor to ask.
我一直在想这个古斯・福林  知道吗
I've been thinking about this Gus Fring, right?
想他总是两点一线
How he never goes anywhere:
一家餐厅  家  一家餐厅  家
one restaurant, home, one restaurant, home,
就这么来来回回
back and forth back and forth?
现在我敢肯定这是他妈狗屁了
Which, now I'm even more convinced is bullshit,
这人另外还有13家餐厅  知道么
because the man owns 13 other restaurants, right?
于是我开始考察他这个小小的商业帝国
So I started thinking about this little empire of his, right?
十四家餐厅  谁在供货
Fourteen restaurants. Who supplies them?
运营的基地在哪里
What's the base of operations?
我简单调查了一下  大发现
So I do a little diggin', and bingo!
这家炸鸡店有个分销基地
Pollos Hermanos has a main distribution center.
离城不远
Uh... It's not far from town.
这地方很大  我是说
The place is huge. I mean--
我正在网上看着呢
I'm looking at it online right now.
我告诉你  这个仓库非常大
I tell you, it's a big warehouse
一排排的家禽养殖场
and rows of these long poultry buildings,
或者是孵化场  随你怎么说
or hatcheries, or whatever you call 'em.
足以藏下非法活动的场所
Lots of space to hide illicit activity.
看起来很有点戏啊
Sounds promising, right?
你怎么说  伙计
So. Whaddya say, buddy?
一起再去实地考察一番吗
Got another field trip in you?
汉克  嗯
You know, Hank. Um...
我是说  听上去很不错
I mean, it sounds great.
真的  可是我
It really does. But I--
你知道的  我从不撒谎
You know, I won't lie, uh--
你正赶上我...
You caught me... somewhat...
身体不适
indisposed.
什么意思  拉稀了?
What do you mean, like taking a dump indisposed?
是啊
Yeah. That's--
真是尴尬  拉稀了
embarrassingly, that's it.
我只是...
You know, it's just...
肠胃不适  整个人都
upset stomach, you know, and everything...
-是啊  -身体失调了
- Yeah. - It's out of control.
实在来得突然
Really explosive.
德州-墨西哥的混合风味太糟了
Bad Tex-Mex.
-就是商场那个  -知道了  知道了
-At the mall.   -Yeah, yeah, yeah.
我懂了  不用说的太详细了
I get it. You don't have to paint me a picture.
出门一趟一个人带尿布就够可以的了
Probably one guy in a diaper is enough for this trip anyway.
是啊  真对不住  汉克
Yeah. I'm sorry, Hank.
嘿  别这样
Hey, don't be.
最近我老是麻烦你
I've been asking a lot of you lately.
很谢谢你
I appreciate it.
我另外请人送我吧
I'll find another ride for this one.
另外请人
Another ride?
对  我肯定能找到别人送我的
Yeah. I'm sure I can get someone else to take me.
比如我的训练师  查克
Uh, my trainer, Chuck.
或许可以问问他
Maybe I'll ask him.
听着  我  我
Look, I'm-- I'm--
这病估计也就一天
This is probably just a 24-hour thing.
至多两天
Maybe 48 hours, at the most.
嗯  你能不能等上
And, um... Do you think you could possibly hold off
一两天
for a day or two?
哎  伙计  我是说  你知道
Aw, jeez, buddy. I mean, I-- You know--
我只是
You know, I just--
我真的是
I would just really...
非常高兴能送你去
love to be the one to be able to-- to take you there, and--
我自己也很愉快
I mean, I have just really enjoyed, you know,
能和你一块度过这段时光
the time with you,
而且还能帮上你的忙
and helping you.
好吧  既然这对你来说这么重要
Okay, sure. If it means that much to you.
等你好了
Just, you know, give me a call
打个电话给我  如何
when you're feeling up to it, all right?
谢谢  我会的  好
Thank you. I will. Okay.
再见
Bye.
-喂  -麦克
- Yeah.  - Uh, Mike.
听着  我只想跟你说
Listen. I just want to say, first off,
首先  别生气
don't be angry.
什么事  沃尔特
What is it, Walter?
我的连襟
My brother-in-law,
我的那位毒品管制局的兄弟
My DEA-- He--
不久之后  他也许就会
Soon, he will probably,
也可以说马上  他会去到
in the near future, take a ride out to
一个特定的分配中心
a certain distribution center,
去调查些东西
to look around for things.
就调查些东西  是的  没错
Look around for things. And... Yeah.
麦克
Mike?
-这些都要送去哪  -其他地方
- Where's this all going? - Elsewhere.
谢谢惠顾  请把单子给您的专业汽车护理专家
Thank you. Please give this to your car care professional.
今天来一个全车手工上蜡
So. A hand wax for you today?
好的  很好
Okay. Great.
请把单子给您的专业汽车护理专家
Please give this to your car care professional.
黑色探索者对吧
And the black Explorer?
我们当然可以清洗您的车地板垫  可说真的
Well, of course we could shampoo your floor mats, but really,
豪华彻底清洗才是您最好的选择
deluxe detailing is the best bang for your buck.
对了  SUV车型要额外收费
Oh, and SUVs are extra.
请把单子给您的专业汽车护理专家
And please give this to your car care professional.
谢谢惠顾
Thank you!
请把单子给您的专业汽车护理专家
Please give this to your car care professional.
你好啊  斯凯
Hey, Sky.
天呐  是你啊  泰德
Oh, my God. Ted.
你来是...
What are you, uh--
我听办公室里的人
Someone from the office, uh,
说你在这工作  所以我想
said you worked down here, so I thought I'd...
来拜访一下
come down and say hi.
你好
Hello.
你看上去气色不错
You look great.
哪有  我都快要
No. I'm gonna like--
也许快要看上去像个疯婆子了
I probably just look crazed.
别瞎说  你看上去很幸福
Not at all. You look happy.
上次我见到你时
Last time I saw you--
你好
Hi, there.
斯凯勒  我之所以来
Uh, thing is, Skyler, um,
是因为我想和你谈谈
I really need to talk to you.
泰德
Ted,
我不认为我们还有什么好谈的了
I really don't think we have anything to talk about.
事实上  我们有
Actually, we do.
一次审计
An audit?
等等  明天要进行一次审计
Wait, an audit tomorrow?
他们多久前通知你的
How long have you had this?
有一段时间了
Awhile.
我一直在做思想斗争  想要不要联系你
I'd... debated, you know, contacting you.
联系我  干吗不直接找个律师  泰德
Contact me? What about a lawyer? Ted--
泰德  这是
Ted, this is--
这可是刑事侦缉处的通知
This is the CID.
属于刑事案件
The Criminal Division.
天哪  你可是面对的重罪的起诉
My God, you facing a felony charge here.
除了已欠的应缴税款外还有十万美金的罚款
$100,000 fine on top of the taxes you already owe,
外加还有五年刑期
plus five years in prison!
是的  情况很糟糕
Yeah. It's bad.
是的  情况的确很糟糕
Yeah. It most certainly is.
听着  我的想法是
Look, here's the thing.
我在想  你是否可以
I was wondering, maybe, if um,
帮我一把
there's some way you could help with this.
帮你一把  怎么帮
Help? Help how?
利用你的帐目知识
Well, with your knowledge of how the books got the way they are,
也许你能够
maybe there's some way you could, uh,
帮我撤销一些账目
undo what's in there.
你要我帮你做假账
You want me to uncook your books?
也许有些方法  或者一些小技巧
Maybe there's some method, or some accounting trick
-你可以用来...  -泰德
- you could, you know, use-- - Ted.
这不会像你所想的那样简单
It doesn't work like that.
木已成舟  无力回天
The damage is already--
我的名字
My name.
那上面都有我的签名
My signatures are all over those books.
斯凯勒  我是责任人  不是你
Skyler, I'm accountable, not you.
我来解释下接下来会发生什么
Let me explain what's gonna happen here, okay?
一旦刑事侦缉处发现这个税收欺诈行为
Once the CID sees this as willful tax fraud,
他们会为你专门立案调查
there are going to build the strongest possible case against you,
而且他们一旦开始了那步
and once they start down that path,
八成你就难逃罪责了
they have an 80% conviction rate.
因为他们被授权获取你的信件
That's because they're allowed to monitor your mail,
窃听你的电话  而且还不仅仅是你的  泰德
and tap your phones-- and not just you, Ted.
只要与这账目有关的人都会被牵连
Everyone involved in those books.
我不能容忍这种事情发生在我身上
I can't have this in my life.
我不能被审计
I cannot be audited.
斯凯勒  你  你
Skyler, you-- you--
你会没事的  他们针对的是我
You're going to be fine, okay? They're after me.
他们只想抓到头目  不是某个洗车房的收银员
It's the captain they want, not some cashier at a car wash.
无意冒犯  对不起
No offense. I'm sorry.
我
I, uh,
我不希望你担心
I don't want you to worry, okay?
我会找到方法解决的
I'm gonna figure out a way through this.
总有办法的
Somehow. Okay?
这里
Here.
就在这
Right here.
他准备杀了他吗
So is he gonna kill him?
谁准备杀了谁
Is who gonna kill who?
古斯
Gus.
他准备杀了怀特老师的连襟吗
Is he gonna kill Mr. White's brother-in-law?
我是说  现在做这些都是因为他  对吧
I mean, he's the reason for all this here, right?
因为干掉这么一个人对他而言很合乎逻辑
Because it's totally logical for him to off the dude.
一个混蛋毒品管制局探员
A-hole DEA agent,
到处找麻烦
pokin' around your junk--
谁想要这种待遇
Who needs that, right?
除掉他似乎
Makes sense to get rid of him...
也合情合理
for good.
可杀了一个警察
But killing a cop--
我不知道
I don't know.
要是调查你的人突然死了
It could look suspicious if, uh,
那样会使你看上去更加可疑吧
the dude who's investigating you suddenly up and dies.
还有怀特先生
Then there's-- there's Mr. White.
如果有家人被杀
Who'd be even more ape shit
谁会怒不可遏
if he had family getting murdered.
他不会再为古斯制毒了
He'd never cook for Gus again.
看来要考虑的事情有很多啊
Guess there's a lot of angles to consider.
如果这个人出事
If something were to happen to the man,
你会有意见吗
would you have a problem with that?
谁会真正在意我怎么想
Who really cares what I think?
婊子养的
Son of a bitch!
你缓一缓  小子  我们得困在这儿一会儿了
You get comfortable, kid. We may be here a while.
-喂  -趴下
- Hey. - Get down!
喂
告诉他们
我同意
-我该问问是怎么回事么  -是我就不多问
- Should I even ask?  - I wouldn't.
怎么回事  这也成了惯例吗
So what is it? Kinda be a regular thing now.
边制毒边处理尸体  老天
Meth cooking and corpse disposal? Jesus.
给我们拿个空桶  沃特
Just grab us a spare barrel, Walter.
这次又是怎么回事
What was it this time?
是哪个倒霉的混蛋  惹恼了古斯
What did this poor bastard do to piss off Gus?
还是古斯又需要作何暗示
Or did Gus just need to send another message?
你闭嘴
Shut your mouth.
你自己闭嘴  否则我来动手
You shut your mouth, or I'll shut it for you.
我不许你对我或杰西说什么
I don't want you talking to me or Jesse.
把桶拿来
Just get the barrel.
如果你想要报警
And if you ever plan on calling the cops
揭发我们任何一人
on one of my guys again,
自便吧  准备好两个桶子
you go ahead and get two barrels.
我有话说
Yo, like, uh,
我从没感谢
I guess I never thanked you for
你救了我
what you did.
多谢
Thanks.
下次  别像个白痴傻站着
Next time, don't stand there like an idiot.
移动脚步  快跑
Move your feet, run and so forth.
但是说真的
But seriously, what--
古斯打的什么算盘
what was the deal with Gus?
-算盘  -那个狙击手
- Deal? - The Terminator shit?
他径直朝子弹走去
Walking right into the bullets?
他到底在干嘛
What the hell was he doing?
卡特尔集团需要古斯
The cartel needs Gus.
需要他的销售网络
His distribution network.
他们不想杀他
They're not looking to kill him.
可是  我们剩下的人  就无所谓了
But what? The rest of us are like, open season?
他会为此有所行动吗
Is he doing anything about that?
还是我们就继续
Or do we just keep hanging out
出去当枪靶  而他...
for target practice while he's--
孩子
Kid.
够了  你有问题的话
Enough. You got questions,
自己去问他
ask him yourself.
还有这里  未上报收入
And here again. Unreported income.
离现在有一年多了
That's more than a year straight so far.
你作何解释呢
Do you want to say something about this?
我看不太懂了
Because I'm having a hard time figuring it out.
我得...
Well, I-- I'd have to, um,
看看收据的复印件
have a look at the copies of the receipts
来提醒提醒我
to refresh my memory.
您请自便  贝内克先生
Take all the time you need, Mr. Beneke.
这是我们此行的目的
That's why we're here.
抱歉我迟到了
Oh, I am so sorry I am late.
我迷路了
I got lost.
-嗨  泰德  -斯凯
- Hey, Ted. - Sky.
这楼太让人困惑了
This building is so confusing.
到处都是门
There are doors everywhere.
嗨  这位是
Hi. You are--
特别探员詹姆斯・贝卡尔斯
Special Agent James Bekaris.
真特别
Ooh. Special.
斯凯勒・怀特
Skyler White.
怀特女士  你是记录这些
Ms. White. You are the accountant
财务报告的会计员
of record for many of these reports.
-是这样吗  -没错
- Is that correct? - Guilty as charged.
也许你可以解释一下
Well then, perhaps you can shed some light
这些遗失收入的记录
on this history of missing revenue.
-遗失  -是的
- Missing? - Uh-huh.
-不会吧  都在这儿  -没有
- No, it's there. - No.
所有的收入都肯定流入了公司的账上
Revenue most definitely flowed through this company.
却没有记录在你们的报表里
But it's not all accounted for in your reports.
我来瞧瞧
Hmm, let's take a look.
这笔记录在这儿呢
Well, you know, this account here?
这是凯勒先生的账户
That is Mr. Keller's account,
凯勒先生是泰德父亲的老友
and Mr. Keller's an old friend of Ted's dad,
他总是电子支付
and he always sends an electronic payment,
这最让我烦了
which personally I hate,
因为我喜欢纸质支票
because I'm a real paper person,
可凯勒先生是环保人士
but Mr. Keller's one of those environmental people.
总之  他不付实体支票
So anyway, since there wasn't a physical check,
我没有记在账本里  不过
I didn't enter it into the book, but...
钱肯定在那儿
the money's there.
怀特女士  你读过工业相关章程第六章吗
Ms. White, you've read Section 61 of the IRC?
我不太明白你说什么
I... did not follow what you just said.
一个企业的总体收入是如何界定的
How gross income for a business is defined.
-你无权这么做  -我想我可以
- You're not allowed to do that. - Well, I think I am.
不  你不可以
No, you're not.
你知道大家的意见各有不同
Well, you know what they say about opinions, right?
人人都有发言权的
Everyone's got one.
但说真的  我可以
But seriously, I am.
不管是电子付账
Look, it doesn't matter if its an electronic check
还是实体付账  收入就是收入
or a paper check, income is income.
你不能不上报
You're not allowed to not declare it.
我把这些都输入进了记账软件
When I input everything into the Quicken,
没有一项标红  就说明
nothing flashed red, so that's gotta mean
没有问题  对吧
it's okay, right?
-使用Quicken?  -是的
-Quicken.   -Uh-huh.
这种规模的公司  你用记账软件做账
You used Quicken to manage books for a business this size.
是啊  你们这里也用吗
I did. Oh, do you guys use that here?
那东西最棒了
'Cause it is the best.
就像电脑上装了计算器  特别神
It's like having a calculator on your computer. Amazing.
怀特女士  你是怎么得到这份工作的
Ms. White, how did you get this job?
泰德雇了我
Oh, Ted hired me.
不  我指的是你的职业证书
No. I mean your qualifications.
你拿的是什么证书
What are your qualifications?
在哪里接受的培训
Where did you get your training?
我倒是没有参加过培训
Ooh, well I haven't had any training per se,
我就是天生擅长处理数字
I've always been naturally good with numbers.
对数字的直觉
Got a good instinct for them.
对吧  泰迪
Right, Teddy?
好吧
Right.
我开始明白了
This is all falling into place now.
怀特女士  我还有一个问题
Ms. White, I just have to ask.
你没有在别处做会计吧
You're not managing accounts anywhere else, are you?
眼下没有
Right now? No.
我现在在洗车场做收银员
I'm a cashier at a car wash.
我不太明白刚才是怎么回事
I'm not really clear about what happened in there.
总之是好事
What happened is good news.
不了解法律并不等于犯罪
Ignorance of the law does not equate to criminality.
不过是无知而已
It equates to ignorance.
你只管把补税缴齐  交上罚金
Look, pay your back taxes, pay the penalties,
该做什么做什么  把这事忘掉
and move on from this. Just put it behind you.
拿什么来缴
Pay with what?
我欠他们61万7千块
I owe them $617,000.
-我拿什么...  -自己想办法  好不好
- What am I... - Look, just figure it out. All right?
你刚刚逃脱牢狱之灾
You just dodged prison.
变卖资产  把那辆宝马处理掉
Sell your assets. Get rid of the BMW,
用房子做二次抵押贷款
take out a second mortgage on your house.
二次抵押  我房子已经被扣了
Take a mortgage? I have a lien on my house.
我已经没有资产  没有可以变卖的了
I don't have any assets. There are no assets left to sell.
泰德
Ted.
如果你不缴罚金  他们就会重启调查
If you don't pay them, they will reopen the investigation.
我刚刚编的那些谎
And that little fiction I just spun up there
立刻就会穿帮
will completely unravel.
你必须想办法解决
You have to settle.
我倒希望能
Wish I could.
请进
Come in.
希望你饿了
I hope you brought an appetite.
算是吧
Yeah. I guess.
麦克说你有疑问
Mike mentioned you have some questions.
对
Yeah.
我们先吃饭  然后再谈
We'll eat first. And then we'll talk.
好的
Right on.
叫我来做什么
What am I doing here?
我知道你很担心
I know you have concerns.
昨天在农场上
What happened yesterday
我的人出了事
to my man at the farm...
那是件可怕的事
It was a terrible thing.
脑袋被打开花的那哥们吗  是吓人
Oh, the dude getting his head blown off? Yeah.
我请你来我家
I have invited you into my home,
烹制菜肴
prepared food,
好跟你坐下来谈谈
so we could sit and talk.
像男人一样  谈生意上的事
Discuss what's going on in this business,
我们的生意
our business, like men.
我会解释现在发生的事情
And I will explain everything that's happening.
解答你的疑问
I will answer your questions.
不过首先  我需要你
But first, I need you...
回答我的一个问题
to answer one question for me.
你能用沃尔特的配方制毒吗
Can you cook Walter's formula?
什么
What?
沃尔特的配方
Walter's formula.
你能制出那种货吗
Can you produce this product?
不借助他人
Without any help, alone?
不能
No.
为什么
Why?
你问我能不能脱离怀特老师  做他的冰毒
You asking me if I can cook Mr. White's crystal? Without him?
就我吗
Me?
一个嗑药的废物
The junkie loser you were about to waste
上个月还差点儿被你宰掉丢进沙漠里的家伙
and dump in the desert a month ago?
这就是你的计划
This is your plan, huh?
请我进来你家  做了这么一桌子东西
Invite me in your house, make whatever this is,
跟我称兄道弟  让我自以为
be my buddy and... and make me feel
是个人物了
important,
然后杀了怀特老师
then get me to keep cooking for you
让我给你继续制毒
after you kill Mr. White.
你乐意像男人一样谈
You want to... you want to talk like men?
我就给你说句男人的话
Let's talk like men!
你要杀怀特老师  就得把我也杀了
You kill Mr. White, you're gonna have to kill me too.
我没有问你这个问题
That is not what I asked you.
你在这里是因为
You are here
与卡特尔集团的关系已经无法维系
because circumstances with the Cartel are untenable.
我需要你的帮助
And I need your help.
我需要你来阻止一场混战
I need you to help prevent an all-out war.
现在  如果你愿意
Now, if you would,
回答我的问题
answer the question.
你要走了
Hey, you get it out?
对
Yeah.
怀特老师
Yo, Mr. White. Hey, uh,
我非常需要跟你谈谈  我...我不知道
I really got to talk to you. I... I don't know
你是在家还是在哪里
if you're with your family or whatever,
但是这事非常要紧  所以我希望
but this is important, so I'm hoping
你能过来一趟
you could come over.
-谢天谢地  -请进
- Thank God.  - Come on in.
你...要啤酒吗
You uh... You want a beer?
-还是喝别的  -不用
- Or something? - No.
-我能坐吗  -好好
- Should I sit down? - Oh, yeah, yeah.
不好意思  你坐
Yeah, sorry. Go ahead.
行  那个...
Okay, so, um...
好吧  那个...
Okay. So...
据说他们...
word has come down that they...
他们想让我去墨西哥
They want me to go to Mexico.
古斯和卡特尔集团
There's some sort of war brewing
现在正在打仗
between Gus and the Cartel.
"有人传话下来"
"Word has come down?"
对  卡特尔集团一直在干扰古斯的生意
Yeah, the cartel has been messing with Gus's operation.
就像一样传递信息
Like jacking trucks to like, send a message,
还记得昨天那个人吗
and you know, yesterday, that dude
我们抬进来的那个
we brought to the lab?
他们就在我眼前把他给毙了
I mean, they shot him right in front of me.
把他脑袋给打爆了
Just blew his head open.
一个狙击手在大老远就对准了他
Some sniper nailed him from like a mile away.
不管怎么样  他们始终不敢接近
Anyway, they've been holding them off,
可一边卡特尔集团为争霸主地位
but between the cartel taking pot shots
一边你的妹夫未查真相  广泛撒网
and your brother-in-law trying to throw a net
你管这叫什么
over the whole deal, it's like, what do you call,
两难境地
a rock and a hard place situation.
所以古斯快抗不住了
So Gus is gonna cave.
所以塔特尔集团
So the cartel wants half
想要分掉古斯的业务的一半
of Gus' entire operation, and they want
还想要你的制毒配方  他打算给他们
your formula, and he's gonna give it to them.
我准备给他们
Well, I-- I gotta give it to them.
我应该去墨西哥
I mean, I'm supposed to go to Mexico
教一帮卡特尔的毒师
and teach a bunch of cartel chemists
如何大量制造冰毒
how to cook a batch of blue.
古斯不相信你  所以...
You know, Gus doesn't trust you, so...
我会去  你才是毒师  伙计
I gotta go-- I mean, you're the chemist, man!
不是我
You know, not me.
比如说  我去
Let's say I go down
到那里  到丛林里去
to, you know, go over there, go to the jungle
或者随便什么地方
or-- or whatever.
比方说他们有真正的化学家
You know, and say they got actual chemists,
比如毒师  问我化学问题
like cartel chemists, asking me chemistry stuff
我都答不上来  因为我不是你
that I don's know how to answer, because I'm not you.
还有  如果所有的设备
And what if all the equipment
都标注的墨西哥语  不是英语怎么办
is uh, is in Mexican, instead of English?
那怎么办
You know? Oh!
我不知道  我不知道
I don't know. I don't know.
如果我搞砸了
I mean, if I mess this up,
我就死定了
I am dead, you know?
我们就都完了
All of us!
怀特老师  听着  我要你帮忙
Mr White. Look, I-- I need your help.
好吧  或许你能
Okay, maybe you could--
或许你能指导我
Maybe you could, like, coach me
或调教一下  行吗  或者给我点注解
or something, you know? Or you can give me some notes.
怀特老师
Mr. White.
所以你见过古斯了
So you saw Gus?
什么  没
What? No.
-你没见古斯  -没
- You didn't see Gus. - No.
那是谁跟你说的这些
Then who told you all of that?
我刚说了  是传的话
It was passed down, like I said.
传的话
Passed down?
谁传的
By whom?
麦克和他们
By, uh... By Mike and them.
是他们说的  他们
They did. They--
所以"他们"不包括古斯
So "They" Doesn't include Gus.
你没和古斯在一起过
You haven't been with Gus.
你没见过古斯  没和古斯说过话
You haven't seen Gus. You haven't spoken to Gus.
你为什么...
Why are you...
你昨晚没在古斯家
You weren't at Gus's house last night.
什么
What?
搞什么鬼
What the hell?
天呐
J-Jesus--
还在这里
It's still here.
-还在  -天呐
- It's still here. - Oh, Jesus.
你看着我的眼睛  告诉我
You look me in the eye and you tell me
你昨晚没在他家
that you weren't at his house last night.
我
I, um...
听着  我没机会
Look, I didn't have a chance.
满意了吗
All right?
好吧  我就知道你会有这反应
Okay, I knew you would react this way.
我就知道你会抓狂
I knew you would freak out
不会信我
and wouldn't believe me--
所以我才没提这事
that's why I didn't say anything.
那里有一大锅汤  你知道吗
Look, there was just this one big pot of stew, okay?
他炖了一大锅东西
He just made this one big pot,
我们都从里面舀了吃  我该怎么办
and we both ate from it-- what was I supposed to do?
毒死自己吗
Huh? Poison myself?
两小时十八分钟
Two hours and 18 minutes,
你就没想出个办法来下毒
and you could have figured a way to give it to him.
-他一直没离开过房间  -你这个骗子
- He never left the room! - You lying little shit!
你只有一件事要做
You had one thing to do!
一件事  只要你做那一件事  我多说一句
One thing! That is the only thing, I might add,
那能救我们俩的命
that would save our lives.
而你当时就在那里  就在他家
And you were right there. You were in his house!
你却没胆量下手
And you didn't have the guts to do it.
两小时十八分钟
Two hours and 18 minutes?
你从没想过要杀他  是吗
You never had any intention of killing him, did you?
你怎么知道我昨晚在他家
How did you know I was at his house last night?
你跟踪我
Were you following me?
这个  我靠的是这个
This. This is how I knew.
你在我的车上装了监视器
You bugged my car?
晚上7点10分到9点28分
7:10 to 09:28 P.M.
两小时十八分钟
Two hours and 18 minutes,
可你从没想下手  对吗
but you had no intentions, did you?
一点念头都没有
Not the slightest intention.
-我为你做了那么多事  -你居然监视我
-Everything that I have done for you,  -you put a bug on my car?
抱歉  你为我做了那么多事
I'm sorry. After everything you've done for me?
你为我做了什么
What you've done for me?
你已经杀了我  这就是你做的
You've killed me is what you've done.
你已经签了我的死刑执行令
You've signed my death warrant.
想听我的建议
And now you want advice?
好  那我就给你建议
All right, I'll give you advice.
去墨西哥把事情搞砸吧  我知道你会的
Go to Mexico and screw up, like I know you will,
然后命丧哪里都不知道
and wind up in a barrel somewhere!
天呐
Oh, God!
能走吗
Can you walk?
能
Yeah.
给我滚  别再回来了
You get the fuck out of here and never come back.